# Erik Halbakken

PMB 6779H PO Box 257 Olympia, WA 98507 c: 425-736-6799 erikhalbakken@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Web developer with a background in banking with 15+ years of experience at Wells Fargo Bank and Wells Fargo Home Mortgage. Proven success in compliance management and customer service. Skilled at multitasking, organization, and self-management. Strong work ethic and unquestioned integrity. Other strengths include:

- Attention to detail
- Priority setting
- Problem solving

- Follow through
- Passion for learning
- Professionalism

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

WELLS FARGO HOME MORTGAGE, WASHINGTON

**APRIL 2012 - PRESENT** 

#### Loan Processor 4, Feb. 2013 - Present

Job functions include: processing, closing and compliance for loan products; interpreting policies while analyzing applicant, property and documentation; ordering all required verifications, documentation and subsequent follow-ups; works as a liaison between mortgage consultant, underwriter, closer and customer. Interact with customers daily and ensure they have a positive experience whether in person, by email or by phone.

## Customer Service Rep 3, April 2012 - Feb. 2013

Assisted mortgage consultants with loan file preparation and review before turning the files in to the loan processors. Responsible for ensuring all required compliance training is completed on time for a staff of approximately 18 people. Reviewed multiple reports to identify areas that need improvement to help drive branch production. Assisted mortgage consultants with ordering title, escrow or asset documentation. Assisted branch manager with various operational tasks on a daily basis. Interacted with customers daily and ensures they have a positive experience whether in person or by phone.

WELLS FARGO BANK, WASHINGTON

FEB. 2003 - APRIL 2012

#### Service Manager 1 & 2. Feb. 2004 - April 2012

Managed a teller team of up to nine employees in a retail branch environment. Some responsibilities include ensuring that teller sales goals are met, transactions are processed accurately, customer service ratings are high, and that overall branch compliance is met and maintained. Also responsible for the creation of quarterly performance reviews for my direct reports, handling customer requests and concerns, and scheduling staff to ensure coverage on a weekly basis.

- · Received invitation and attended the Circle of Excellence Washington Sales and Service recognition event
- Hand selected by branch manager to assist in the opening and managing of the Redmond Ridge location which, at the time, was the first brand new branch located in Washington in ten years
- Successfully passed all nine Store Operational Control Reviews
- Selected by District Manager to participate in the Buddy Banker Program in 2010 and 2011
- Received the I Am Wells Fargo award in 2009

• Received invitation and attended the *Best by Northwest* Region Sales and Service recognition event and was awarded the *Star Manager* award

### Lead Teller, Aug. 2003 - Feb. 2004

Assisted customers with day to day transactions and strove to enhance their banking relationship by making product recommendations. Performed transaction approvals for other tellers and was responsible for the creation of the weekly schedule.

- Promoted to Service Manager within six months of receiving the lead teller promotion
- Achieved Gold level status multiple times in relation to my sales production
- Successfully performed certain Service Manager duties in the absence of a branch Service Manager

# Teller, Feb. 2003 - Aug. 2003

Assisted customers with day to day transactions and strove to enhance their banking relationship by making product recommendations.

- Promoted to Lead Teller within the first six months of employment
- Achieved Gold level status multiple times in relation to my sales production

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Washington Coding Boot Camp 2019

Cascadia Community College, Bothell, WA 2004-2007

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery